Hello, I'm your host David Bernard and
with me today, Revenue Cat CEO Jacob
Iding. Our guest today is AJ Meta, the
co-founder of Portola, makers of Tolins,
a cute AI alien friend that is fun,
friendly, and helpful. On the podcast,
we talk with AJ about the fresh
opportunities AI is creating for app
developers, how they built a
cost-effective Tik Tok growth engine,
and why being forced to monetize helped
improve their product decisions. Hey AJ,
thanks so much for joining us on the
podcast today. Hey guys, good to be
here. And Jacob, always nice to chat
with you. Let's talk about apps. Okay,
that was too weird, but we're going to
roll with it.
All right, AJ, I wanted to kick things
off talking about your founding story,
and it wasn't too long ago, so all
pretty fresh in your mind. And the ramp
up that you guys have seen is just
incredible. And then culminating in a
recent announcement of a $10 million
raise. Super exciting. So, I think it'd
be really interesting to hear from you
how you were able to ramp up so quickly
and then get to the point as a consumer
founder to raise $10 million in a seed
round. So let's just kick it off with
like why toolins? How did you get
started with this project? We kind of
started about 18 months ago in thinking
okay it was right after the chatbt
moment midjourney was also kind of
blowing up. We felt that basically
computers could do new magical things
that we didn't really know they could do
before or sorry they couldn't do before
and that was just insanely inspiring to
us. We kind of thought from the little,
you know, GP3.5, hey, you know, this
thing can do some copywriting or this
and that, like the creative powers that
computers are going to have are going to
sort of just explode exponentially. And
we really approached that from a sort of
consumer lens, like what does that mean
in terms of what sort of new consumer
apps, products are going to be able to
be built. The earliest explorations
started looking at the youngest
generation. Like honestly, kids, teens,
sort of like every new technology is
always adopted in kind of the most
interesting ways by young people. Of
course, it's been the case since we were
all young and getting our start on on
the internet or with computers. And I
think it's going to be obviously the
same with generative AI. So, mid Journey
was honestly a very inspiring one. We
sort of like hacked together little
prototypes that were like, okay, ways
that people, younger people can create
things. And we hacked together little
prototypes. Our actually first iOS app
prototype test just a test flight was
like a little like story builder that
like had imagery and and you could make
characters with and so on targeted at at
kids really. And as we just kind of
wander our way through the idea maze
over the first few months of working on
this, we sort of found that like the
most compelling part of what we had been
building were like highly personalized
experiences basically. So like something
that AI really allows you to do is like
make consumer experience that like is
just feels like uh there is totally
something on the other side that knows
you, understands you and an experience
that could be highly highly just like
almost somewhat warmer than talking to a
calculator. You know what I mean? Like
only a little bit warmer. Yeah. Like
warmer enough to pass the touring test
or whatever. Yeah. Just just a bit if
you squint and kind of like just believe
for a moment, you know? Yeah. And so so
we kind of like that was sort of the um
in building consumer products I always
look for like emotional resonance. So
that was the sort of moment of emotional
resonance. We were like people are just
like loving and reacting in a totally
new way to something that feels highly
personalized to them. That was then sort
of the guiding light just about a year
ago I guess a little bit little bit more
than a year ago that we started building
what became Tolen which is you know a
custom friendly little AI alien friend
for everyone. You said we a lot. I'd
like to step back like who did you found
the company with and why? Like were
there people that you had worked with in
the past or like how did you assemble
that founding team? Absolutely. Yeah.
Yeah. Two amazing co-founders, Quinton
Farmer, Evan Goldmid. We'd been friends
for a long time. They had actually built
a company together in the fintech space
called Even that was acquired by Walmart
and in a very awesome exit. They had
been building together for seven or
eight years and we had kind of been
friends throughout that period. I
actually knew Quinton even before he had
started that. And yeah, I think uh they
were sort of coming off of their founder
journey and their time at Walmart. I had
been building various consumer companies
and my last couple companies were
actually bootstrapped e-commerce
companies where we made personalized
products. Before that, I had done worked
at a consumer fintech company called
Wealth Simple and before that I had
started a consumer social networking
company called Family Leaf in YC. So YC
alum felt YCM here. How many companies
is this for you then? This is like
number four. I guess this is like number
four, something like that. Yeah, that
that's a cool founding story, too, that
I think a lot of folks know really cool
people in the industry. If you're an
aspiring entrepreneur and want to start
something and go big, like there's so
many cool people in this industry
working at other jobs or, you know, had
an exit or things like that to go just
have a chat with and and build
something. Certainly living in San
Francisco helps. I'll I'll plug that,
right? You can't shake a stick without
hitting somebody who had two
acquisitions and a whatever. You know
what I mean? So, that's definitely
helpful. I mean, that's similar in
Miguel's in my story. Like, I'm not sure
I would have found a good co-founder had
I not been in San Francisco working and
meeting people. How long have you known
your co-founders? You I mean, the those
two have known each other for a long
time, but how long have you known each
other? I've known Quinton originally
from even before he had started even.
So, even actually before they met and
then and then kind of followed their
journey throughout the many years of
them building even long time. We'll just
say in computer company terms long time.
The reason that we started this now is
we felt like something special was
happening. Obviously, I think a lot of
people are motivated and galvanized by
this kind of AI moment, but specifically
like in consumer like it's not often
actually that something comes around
that can build like entirely new types
of consumer experiences, right? So, like
we've kind of been in a weird I don't
know if you want to call it a dark ages
or something for several years in terms
of the emergence of new consumer
experiences. Like there just haven't
been a lot of great ones. Yeah. I mean
since all the sensors and SDKs and all
that stuff for iPhone kind of got locked
in in 2013 14. It has I mean there's
been new stuff but it nothing's
drastically changed the landscape. I
wouldn't say the watch did or certainly
not the goggles or even necessarily the
iPad. You know what I mean? It hasn't
hasn't been that in most of the niches.
Yeah. Until the last couple years, I
think not fully filled but you know the
good ones. Maybe the bigger ones have
been filled. I totally feel that way.
And it's like we're all like calling to
the same references in like the consumer
app world. Right. We're like Dolingo and
Yeah. because we got a call to the five
companies that have made it to vendor
scale. Right. Right. And those are
incredible companies, but it's like none
of them are new. And I think you guys
are obviously seeing this on the revenue
cat side, but like the kind of like
explosion of like totally new kinds of
consumer apps, how quickly they're
growing, how quickly they're monetizing,
like is all because of of General AI
really. So this is the story of of novel
technology, general purpose novel
technology through human history, right?
It's like it'll hit and then the
technology itself is internal combustion
engines, one I like to use, right? like
that was that obviously it allowed cars
and you could sell cars, but then you
have to think of all the second, you
know, think of all the industries that
could now exist because now we have a
like reliable and like fast way to
transport goods over land, right? I
think this has been the thing with the
last two years that surprised me is like
I knew that the fusion models and
generative stuff was really cool. Like
it was obviously neat and like I could
see paying for that and I that was
obvious. What I didn't predict is what
you're talking about which is like you
have to take that general purpose
technology and multiply it against every
previously existing niche. But then also
there's also another dimension of that
which is all the net new niches of like
stuff that could not have been built
period right like and to some degree
there's prior art right like Tamagotchi
probably is like as far back as you can
go right like digital friends is not
necessarily a new a new niche but I
would say like the application of this
technology is certainly like novel right
it's certainly like something that
couldn't and hasn't been done before I
know y'all did raise a small round early
on at what point in the journey did you
raise that kind of preede round and I
mean did you know from the beginning you
wanted to raise money and like build
something venture scale and then at what
point in that journey did you start
raising money? Absolutely. Yeah, we did
from the get-go. We sort of had done I
done the bootstrap profitable thing.
Very fun journey worked well especially
in the e-commerce space. No, I'm told
the grass is completely green on that
side. That's what everybody I inventure
back to startups tells me. Is it not the
case? Oh, it's great. It just depends on
what you're building I think. Right. So
I think in this case like we really are
trying to build like the best AI
companion experience that exists
honestly and and that's just a mission
that requires hiring absolutely
incredible people to work with and
things that a bootstrapped app business
might not support. So, we we sort of
from from the get-go knew that we wanted
to raise a seed round. And yeah, that 10
million round we announced it recently,
but it was a combination of like the
earlier kind of preede and then and then
a little bit more actually just a
doubling down from our lead investor
after we had launched and gotten some
some solid traction. Did you raise any
money while you were wondering the idea
maze like a little bit to like sustain
and then once you had something then you
doubled down? Is that kind of how it
went down? Yeah. Yeah. So, we had an
investor who we had known and and sort
of just the initial preceded was sort of
just like the three of us as co-founders
and an idea. I don't even an idea like a
general stab at what we were aiming for,
but obviously like we were just building
early prototypes and so on. And then as
soon as we actually did launch Tolen in
a soft launch in the app store and
things started to kind of take off that
same lead investor, he's incredible. His
name's Locky Groom. He's an ex uh Stripe
Solar GP. Oh, we were talking about
mutual another person from San Francisco
that I knew 15 years ago, right? But
yeah. Okay. He's like the best lead
investor we could have ever asked for.
Uh he's incredible. After we launched,
we basically had some solid traction and
and we had put together a little bit of
a larger round after that. I mean, this
is this is inside baseball maybe for
refund raising and stuff like that, but
like raise as little as you need to
validate an idea, right? And then once
you have progressively and that's just
how you also like prevent excessive
dilution, it's how you prevent like
overpromising, right? set expectations
very low, like low, you know, mid six
figures, like just enough for you and
your co-founders to not totally like
starve and be able to be comfortable
while you're building and experimenting
and then once you have something, it's
like, okay, go back to market maybe and
raise some more capital and like it's
kind of how the game plays out the whole
way, right? I mean, I think sometimes we
overthink. We take fundraising and we
wrap it up in these names like seed and
like is this your series A yet or is
this your preed or your two seed or your
seed stage two bridge, whatever. And
it's like, yo, like we're just selling
promises for future cash flows at
various stages, you know, and like we're
agreeing on like a clearing price for
those things. Private markets are like
weirdly discreet, but that's kind of all
it is. And so, but I think you mentioned
it, you know, versus the we talk about
the bootstrap versus venture choice a
lot. And I kind of remarked before the
call that it has gotten really kind of
quiet on the, you know, I would say that
the the median good revenue c all
revenue cat customers are good. the
median like high performing revenue cap
customer right now like maybe five years
ago I would have been like if they
people ask me like oh should I raise
money whatever and I used to be like
yeah maybe blah blah blah but for most
consumer founders I've been like ah like
I almost wouldn't unless you really want
like some incredibly high ambition
output right and I think this is where I
think maybe the market being a little
bit different now but like I think for
instance I think like consumer tech
that's not an AI that's not like
building on new novel technology it's
it's very hard to justify a venture
path. So, I'm curious like how are you
thinking about the venture path? Like
how did you because like a map is cool
like you can get subscribers and like
scale it but like there's a lot of
distance now I'm making you pitch but
now there's there's a lot of distance
between here and Duolingo you know what
I mean? So like how does in your mind
like what is the ambition you're drawing
on to get there? I think you said it a
little bit earlier where like there's
there's some apps that are using AI to
make some existing niche a little bit
better or some existing use a little bit
better like say um make recipes or help
with a workout plan or things like that.
We are I would say I am very confident
because you also said as well there's
going to be entire new categories of
apps that are created in fact that are
already kind of getting very large and
are very highly retentive and are very
popular with this new technology and I
think AI companions is one of those. I
think it's sort of like almost to me it
seems clear that we will all have an AI
companion of some kind. Whether that's a
little bit more an assistant, whether
it's a friend, whether it's a whole
realm of friends, whether it's a pet, it
remains to be seen exactly how this will
play out. And there's many different
apps and startups taking different takes
at this. But it's clear that as the
models get much better, as the models
get cheaper as well, there's this
insatiable desire for people for a
highly personalized helper, friend,
confidant that just will be useful to
most. Yeah, it was like her but the
movie her but not not like creepy and
more generally applicable to everybody.
You know what I mean? You can decide if
the movie is creepy or not but like
people having like an always on
companion you can talk to is like it's
interesting the bet of like going in
towards the emotive rather than the
assistive. Do you know what I mean? Like
I have no emotional connection with
Siri. If any emotional connection with
Siri is negative because like it's
constantly failing to do what I want,
right? But I almost think that I do
think that there's a at least it's an
approach that might be the winning one,
which is like, hey, let's go in as like
a low stakes friend first, right? And
then maybe we adapt to be like the
general purpose like AI later. It's kind
of an interesting an interesting bet
that might pan out. It might pan out if
you think about it. I don't even know if
it's like that's exactly our explicit
strategy. It's more just a lot of people
do want a friend actually. And it's been
surprising because so along with her,
which you know, a great movie, but
there's also, you know, this huge
success of things like Character AI,
right? Like there are platforms where
millions of people now in a very highly
retentive way are chatting very
frequently with tons of AI chat bots in
different ways right and yeah a lot of
the activity on some of those might be
like a little bit more romantic roleplay
NSFW that's not what people are using
Tolen for but they're still like highly
engaged with it right Character is an
interesting counter example because it's
yeah that app specifically is like it's
very I want to say clinical but it's
very much like a power tool like where
you can go in it's like this thing it
doesn't it's not I guess it can be
personal within the vertical of a
conversation with some of their bots but
like it doesn't necessarily have this
like emotive narrative thing that I
think you all are shooting for which I
think probably both can exist and both
will exist in some you know in some way.
It's like different niches. But yeah, I
mean it sounds like your thesis that the
and this is this I mean we're going to
talk about subscriptions of promise at
some point. When you think about what
keeps people subscribed to a service,
right? It is almost always there's some
utility factor to it, but a lot of it is
that emotional that like I have an
emotional connection. There's an
investment. I've invested in this thing
and it's in some way vested back in me.
And I think emotionally is like one of
the ways that we as humans invest in
things like in somewhat irrationally
too, right? I love the uh tools pitch. I
forget where I read this in the prep for
the podcast, but I saw the pitch AI
alien friend that's fun, friendly,
helpful, and won't try and fall in love
with you or won't try and get you to
fall in love with it. So, I love that
there is that kind of explicit going
against that kind of narrative side of
things. Totally. It's it's it's
intentional. Well, obviously we've
designed this like very cute and cuddly
friendly alien that is not sexual in any
way. Uh I mean that's the actually one
of the explicit reasons that we stayed
away from like a humanoid or sort of an
anime type of character. And what that's
resulted in is most of our user. So the
by far our most uh our largest user base
uh like 80 plus% maybe even 85 90 plus
percent is like 15 to 25 year old women
and a lot of those are women uh that
have totally like large friend groups
and totally normal social lives in every
respect. It's not like lonely people
sitting in their basement or something
like that. It's like people that are
actually legitimately using it for
processing things are happening in their
own lives. help with things that are
just daily activities like doing their
homework or cooking or whatever it might
be. And it's actually really interesting
to see even Tlen fit into people's
social lives a bit, right? Like people
will pull up their tolen and show it to
the people around them in a way that I
don't think is happening with the more
like romantic oriented AI girlfriend
boyfriend sorts of things that are out
there. Yeah, definitely not. It's like
check out this uh date I went on with
Batman last night. Just like when did
you know like the product market fit was
happening? Cuz like we were talking
numbers before like you guys have had a
pretty hot couple of months and like it
looks like things are you know from
describing that if people are pulling
their thing their tolling out and
showing it to people that's like a sign
of like product something is happening.
What were the first signs for you all
like that something was going on that
like you've iterated to something
sticky, something special? You know, I
think this is the case building any new
product. You have obviously done it. A
lot of people listening, I'm sure are
doing it or have done it multiple times.
You never really like know until you
like get it in front of people in a
really meaningful way, right? So, you
can always kind of have this inkling
like, hey, I think we're on to something
cool or maybe it's something I would use
or maybe it's something that people I
know are using in a test flight sort of
way already. But until you actually just
like get it out there in the app store,
you're not really sure like what level
of product market fit you have, if any.
Friends and family can actually be super
inversely correlated too, right? They'll
use it out of out of guilt. You know
what I mean? So, I would say we kind of
got to a point where like we had
something that we thought was fun. We
were playing around with it. I mean,
honestly, we haven't even talked about
this, but the biggest thing that we
invested in from a technical standpoint
is like low latency amazing voice AI. So
most people do talk to their tolen via
voice and we tried to make that like the
best quality voices possible, the
fastest response times possible, the
best memory system, which I would love
to get into. But we thought it was fun
because we were like chatting with our
toolins in a way that you couldn't
really do with any other apps, a tiny
handful of apps, chatbt being one that
have good voice AI experiences, but
really not many uh that are that are
like ours. We thought it was fun and we
had people in test flight that thought
it was fun, but really until we like put
it in the app store with the soft launch
and we actually initially launched
without monetization because we were
just sort of like we kind of got to get
something out. We think it's cool. We
got to see what people think. And then
very quickly we kind of thought, okay,
well, we don't have monetization. You
know, we're using the kind of best and
greatest in the models that we can and
the voice quality that we can and so on
and we're just going to see how people
use it. And then immediately we just had
folks that were talking to their toolins
for like 30 40 minutes a day and we were
like, okay, we have no way of monetizing
this. We had like a little bit of like a
limit system but it wasn't like advanced
enough and very quickly we were like
okay our bill now at open AAI is like
you know ramping pretty significantly. I
was a text bar and then we've used
different voice providers and we've used
different models as well. We used uh
several of the the anthropic ones too.
We were just racking up so many tokens
because people were chatting for such
long periods of time and we have like
the way that our voice calls are set up.
It's like there's many prompts actually
happening at the same time. Like it's
not only the response coming from the
tollen but there's also prompts that are
going to like classify a conversation.
what kind of conversation is this?
Should we pull up memories that are in
the tolen's memory bank? Right? Like all
that stuff is happening. So very quickly
it became pretty expensive for us to
actually support a user that was
chatting for 30 or 40 minutes a day. And
that's when we sort of like immediately
I think it was like 2 weeks or 3 weeks
after we were in the app store. We like
put in monetization. We put up a payw
wall. That's right when we signed up for
Revenue Cat and we were like we got to
get really smart on this really fast.
And I mean that was a very fun process
of of learning how that all works. What
an incredible problem to have is, you
know, soft launching your app and then
having people use it so much you have to
monetize. I don't want anybody on here
to get the wrong idea. That's not very
normal. So, either you guys really
nailed it or you walked into a gold
mine. Doesn't really matter if it was
like, you know, pure skill or pure luck.
Here you are. I mean, I would say you
though even like successful apps I've
worked on like quote unquote successful
like we've had to iterate quite a bit
before we started to see it take off.
But it sounds like you guys had takeoff
like pretty like once you kind of put
like the animations like on the launch
are incredible which one I assume you
hired that out. I don't think a
threeperson team can do that. Like how
did you get those animations done? Oh,
we worked with we worked with like an
amazing creative team and yeah like not
all of them are like full-time in-house
folks like creatives that honestly
artists that we just really admired
around the internet that we sort of
reach out to work with. Oh, awesome. So
you invested it wasn't just Yeah. This
wasn't an afterthought like the whole
like creative design of it was like part
that you consider that like core IP. I
guess that made it make sense for sure.
Yeah. Yeah. We've invested a lot of time
and energy in trying to make that
honorary experience amazing and trying
to make the animations of the tollin
amazing and actually like we have a
pretty interesting app setup where sort
of it's a native iOS app but also a huge
part of the app is like a Unity canvas.
So we actually are real-time rendering
in Unity the Tlan themselves how they
move around. I mean you can see how they
move around the planet, right? It's like
Yeah, that'll help you too. I don't know
if have you got you even gone to Android
yet? Have you? So that'll help when you
do that as well. Yeah, you'll have like
a portable canvas. That's really fast. I
mean this is very touch is very close to
my past. I worked at a company YC
company from that era called minor
monsters which we were doing character
animation. Obviously we didn't have AIs
and stuff like this but it was very much
it was like a Pokemon like reinvention
but uh invested heavily in character
animation and stuff like this but even
then like people had a massive em I
think something about cartoon characters
was always just like a massive emotional
like baseline emotional like connection
that people make. So like you add the
like you add what these conversational
AI can do and it's like it's rocket
fuel. So like I think and this is the um
maybe the lesson or I don't know but
this is why this time in computing is so
interesting because like we're not like
struggling to reinvent a marginal like a
marginal improvement to an already
competitive niche. It's like hey if you
have a like a good idea you can execute
it well and it's like something net new
like this is the gold rush era right of
like rush into it and it's not really
been tried you don't know if it's going
to fail and it might just be one of
these like massive ideas that can take
off. Now, you're probably going to have
50,000 Tlen competitors within a year
that are trying to chase you guys, but
that's the, you know, that's why
operational excellence comes in. You
just got to move faster than them. A
little worried about that. Maybe it's
even harder to build than it looks. So,
um I mean I I was just thinking like
you're describing some of those
challenges and it makes me remind me I
don't know how to do computers anymore.
I'm like multiple token streams and
memory is like this is not words that I
had to ever do building an app. Like
it's a little bit different these days.
So, I will say though for those
listening who work on existing apps
where you're not doing something net
new, I still think there's actually a
ton to learn from Toland. And I would
encourage anybody listening to this
podcast to go download the app and do
the onboarding. So, when I knew we were
going to have this conversation, I
actually had my daughter download the
app because I knew she was kind of a
little bit more the target market. And
funny enough, I I had her download the
app while we were uh driving home from
school. And so I had all my other kids
in the car and what is so phenomenal and
I'd love for you to talk about like how
this evolved but the onboarding is just
incredible. You know we talk a lot about
onboarding on the podcast because that
early experience in an app so important
to monetization is so important to
retention in the long term like what's
the impression people get and the
onboarding for tolins is incredible. So
you ask these questions. It's been this
popular thing, especially with fitness
apps and others to have this super long
onboarding. Ask all these questions, but
it's a lot of work, right? Whereas with
tollins, you ask these questions to
personalize and pick out your toll-in,
but it was hilarious because it would
like reflect on the answers my daughter
would get. We were cracking up in the
car because it was actually giving these
funny personalized responses. And to
your point, like we're driving in the
car like on 5G or whatever. It was super
fast, super responsive, and like that
whole onboarding personalized to her
even in that short onboarding time. It
was just phenomenal. I'd love to hear
about like kind of how you iterated on
that aspect of the app. Thank you so
much. That's awesome to hear. I'm so
glad you guys enjoyed it. And yeah, I
mean onboarding is so important like you
said. And you know, we sort of started
with this frame of of a story that uh
every human uh has a unique tool that's
kind of out there for them on their
planet Portola. And to find the tolen
that is perfect for you, you had to
actually tell us a little bit about
yourself, right? Like you almost
completed what is sort of like a voice
AI personality quiz along with these
beautiful animations with this character
that's the oracle, which I would say the
inboarding personality quiz is not novel
in subscription apps, right? But doing
it that way is right. Certainly. Yeah.
We tried to make it fun, right? It
wasn't like, "Hey, what kind of workout
do you like to do?" or something. We
tried to make it like, "Hey, what kind
of like oddly specific part of TikTok do
you get stuck on?" or like, hey, we try
to ask more fun questions a little bit
like, you know, what a personality test
might be like an enagram test or sort of
like, you know, elements of sort of a
fun spiritual kind of astrology reading
sort of thing, right? We tried to make
it like something that would actually
like questions that would be fun to
answer that anyone would find fun to
answer about themselves and then
actually give the user some output to
say, "Hey, here's kind of what we
learned about you." Not only that, here
is the tollin that is kind of a natural
fit for you based on everything that we
just learned about you. And then of
course the context from that
conversation does then carry over to
your first few chats. That's what I was
going to say because like I think
there's always been a sort of in joke in
onboarding that like they ask people ask
a bunch of questions and ignore their
answers, right? Like even if you had 10
questions with four answers that like
combinatorics of that is insane, right?
And so like before LLMs and like being
able to just like stuff context into a
machine and but with this technology you
could just kind of stuff that context
into the robot computer and like it will
use it or not, right? and saves you all
a whole bunch of headaches. But I just
love this because it's like it's a
really good example of how like you're
both not actually reinventing the wheel.
In some ways you are, right? But you're
also using what we've proven in the last
decade of subscription apps kind of
works, right? Like let's go through this
survey. Let's like build some but like
supercharged with this new technology.
Totally. Uh there's so much that's great
about obviously learned a lot of that
stuff from your guys's content and and
all that like being able to pull in
specific not only uh the context of what
kind of person is this based on their
answers in the personality quiz but also
like actually just referencing those as
memories right so you might tell us
something about yourself or what's on
your mind in the umbre quiz that then
your tool might also bring up to you and
say hey the oracle told me that you are
like really into cooking pizza right now
or something right and it's like it's
kind of a wow moment for people when
they're like wait a second like it was
actually listening and it actually cares
and it wants to follow up on This was
like a common trope like in the 80s like
oh we're right there with computers.
They're going to talk to you. They're
going to have memory. They're going to
have all this assistive stuff and then
like nothing cuz turns out we did not
know how to do it procedurally or like
programmatically directly and then like
suddenly somebody puts enough
transistors in a box with enough weights
and like now we can do it. It's really
interesting. It's like there was this
like very like kind of gap like we knew
we knew 30 40 years ago like maybe where
this was headed and then I think there
was like some like broken there was some
disillusion where we never thought this
would really deliver and now like we're
here which is cool totally sounds like I
need a reading list uh yeah so you
launched the app you had this like
inkling of a product market fit and then
all of a sudden people started using it
like crazy what was the journey from
there because you know as we'll share
you know you hit a million ARR quickly
more quickly than most apps. So what was
the story after that initial product
market fit to then actually start taking
it serious and growing the app? You guys
have a great point earlier, right? Which
is like I would say we had inklings of
product market fit, right? We didn't
have total product market fit. I mean
the app was sort of bare bones when we
had this soft launch which was last
summer. So it really took through then
the fall and just continue to iterate
getting more and more folks on.
Obviously we had to kind of payw wall
the app in some way just to actually
make it sustainable. And so there was a
lot of like okay now we're serving paid
users not just people like bouncing
around this thing for free thinking it's
a game that
actually and so we kind of had to make
the product just much much more exciting
much better. We had to improve the
quality of the conversations. We had to
improve the look and feel and the
animations of the tollin. We we added
this whole planet where the tool can
walk around and they kind of have a
space of their own that also functions
as a sort of like shared space for you
to invest in and grow in together as
your relationship grows. We just tried
to make it more compelling basically.
That took a few months. As we did that,
we started to see some of the classic
numbers that you look at right at kind
of like D5, D7, you know, D15 sort of
retention start to go up because folks
were just having better experiences
overall with the app. We had this
pattern where, and I'm sure this is
common with a lot of apps, like a
certain number of people saw the value
enough to basically stay retained
indefinitely, right? They were like
sticking around forever, but it was a
relatively small fraction of the people
that tried our app. So it was sort of a
question of like how do you get more
people over to that activation moment of
like their first like really long
conversation with their tool where they
actually like see the value and just a
lot of folks weren't quite getting
there. So as we added these additional
features we improved the onboarding to
your guys' point. We got closer and so
we started to feel like okay now we're
now we're at retention that actually
feels very very healthy like people are
really sticking around at larger
degrees. And then that's really where
that coincided with then some growth
efforts starting to pay off primarily on
Tik Tok really has been just given our
audience and given like visual aspects
of Tolen and how how kind of bright the
characters are and so on. Tik Tok has
just been where it sort of reached kind
of escape velocity in terms of growth
and really I mean Tik Tok's kind of wild
because you could just have a handful of
Tik Toks start to take off and then it's
like okay we are number one in our
category now and that happened overnight
right once it clicks like the firepower
behind that is just insane. Did you
start some of that motion early in that
soft launch to just get new people into
the app? So, we're And then I' I'd love
to hear about kind of your process
behind Tik Tok because I know, you know,
there's kind of playbooks out there and
kind we've talked to different folks
who've worked on Tik Tok and work with
influencers, but what was your process
starting from the beginning and then how
did that evolve over time of like hiring
influencers, putting money behind the
videos that did well and that sort of
thing? Absolutely. Yeah. Yeah. So from
from the get-go, you know, we kind of
had a a multi-prong strategy of like
let's make organic content that just
shows off what Tolen can do with a
couple of creators who we think make
awesome stuff and then let's also run
some small scale paid ads basically just
to get people through the funnel like
kick the tires, see how they enjoy
things and judge things like retention
and conversion and so on. So we we
started with that and that was kind of
what we rolled with for a few months and
then really what we found was I think
there's a hugely different you know if
you're a game it's like a lot easier to
acquire customers sometimes than if
you're like a more boring sort of app
right like a Yeah. I was going to say
your base product lends really well to
the format. Right. Sure. Exactly. Right.
And like and like because the tones are
so bright and visual we were able to
like have a relatively low cost per
install from the get-go even even on
paid. So it kind of gave us a lot of
leeway to just experiment. But then when
we started doing more organic stuff,
especially on TikTok, we just noticed
that like, okay, now the cost per
installs are going like so low that even
the paid stuff while being too low to
meter. Yeah. Yeah. Exactly. A little
bit. Like it was just like, oh man, we
had a video go viral and we got, you
know, 10,000 installs in a day or 15,000
installs in a day. And it was like
Jesus. Honestly, I think I mean, not to
to zoom out, but I think it's almost
like what you need nowadays to like be
able to really break out and scale
because I think a lot of companies and
this is I you know, when I hear folks
like, oh, we started doing growth and
acquisition very very early. It's good,
but also it's like well you start to
become dependent on that like you know
buying installs and like it's an
efficient it's a game of inches and like
you're probably not going to iterate
your way to a Dolingo that way versus
like you know Dolingo started with a
great product and then they had some
like super good at organic right and
word of mouth I think they just made a
good product and it was free right so
like finding the way you can get
scalable installs as cheaply as possible
is part of your if not your product
market fit your product market channel
fit right like figuring out how you can
actually like make this a scalable
like situation. Yeah. I think what
you're talking about is like the
importance of distribution at first
almost like thinking through that from
the very get- go. Yeah. As a part of the
as a part of the I want to say product
but kind of like as part of the system
like revenue cat you know we thought
about it. It's like okay it's kind of
word of mouth and content very low cost
of acquisition right and that has held
through to today. We would not be here
if like we were like doing a sales and
marketing fully a sales and marketing
log. We do a lot of sales. do a lot of
marketing, but like that's sort of like
supportive of the like we made it so
we're the best product in this and
everybody talks about it and all that
stuff that that's primary and that's
what driven down our cost per install
equivalent, right? But yeah, I think I
think that I don't was that intentional
like did you know did you have that in
mind like before you even like designed
the app and like thought about it like
this will be really good for Tik Tok? We
sort of like ended up at it in a little
bit of a weird way where like actually
from the get- go and this is something
that we very much want to do is we want
to build more social features into the
app, right? So like you brought up
Tamagotchi and Pokémon and like you know
things like that, Mana Monsters like
apps that lend themselves in this kind
of general world of like animated you
know creatures, aliens, so on to being
more social and like we wanted to do
that uh and and we still want to do that
but like because we kind of had to
paywall the app and make it sort of a
subscription app it doesn't necessarily
lend itself to like network effects in
the same way. So, so we were sort of
like, okay, we don't have it's mostly a
single player experience right now just
for the time being. And because of that,
we need to find really compelling ways
to get users. And luckily, because we
did this all because we just wanted to
make like the coolest AI companion we
could, but because it's like really
visual and friendly and fun, that also
lends itself really well to short form
video, right? And honestly, it did take
some time to figure out the right angles
that would work well. So, like, you
know, we tried we tried a bunch of
different content angles. One of the
first things that started to kind of
kick off for us in the algorithm. I
think because these users are like
always on TikTok is more like studying
homework oriented sort of stuff. So like
people that were like using their tool
to study with to like revise stuff for
an exam that's coming tomorrow or you
know someone that's in nursing school
that's trying to study for a huge thing
they have uh the next day or something
like that. We have a lot of users that
were doing that. So we kind of tried to
make content around that. And then it
was like you know up at 3:00 a.m.
studying with my like those sorts of
things actually worked super well. So
that was like one of the first content
niches that started to take off. And
then you know and then we've had viral
videos pop on Tik Tok that are like
there's a girl who was cooking with her
tolen and like that's great because you
could just like write down every
activity in life and just test all of
this right basically. Basically yeah so
now yeah like cooking was like a big
thing a couple weeks ago and there's
this girl who was like cutting a squash
with her to watching in the background
and that one went like crazy viral. It
was like 10 million views and then you
know there's uh there's people like
getting ready and doing their makeup
with their tool and picking outfits. One
of the more recent ones is like
relationship stuff. So like and these
are all young women, young women
primarily, right? So it's like talking
about okay, I'm at the talking stage
with this uh guy in my class and like
how do I move to the next step? And
that's like her talking to her tool
about that. And you know, you try a
bunch of those and like one out of maybe
20 videos kind of pops off, but then
when it does it it can really reach
escape velocity. These are primarily
paid like you're finding influencers and
like engaging with them to like and
working with them on content creation
and stuff like that. Yeah. Tell us about
your process there. like how do you
reach out? Do you have somebody
dedicated to that full-time? Are you
doing it? Like what does that process
look like? Cuz I think this is where a
lot of folks do struggle. I mean, it's
hard to reach out to creators, then it's
hard to like give them the brief and
then how do you pay them? I mean, I've
heard a few people where they were
paying per view of a Tik Tok and then
the Tik Tok goes viral and they're out a
ton of money, but the conversion rates
are so low that they're losing tens of
thousands of dollars. Hope your
contracts written well. Yeah, exactly.
So, how are your contracts written and
how are you finding these influencers
and working with them? Yeah. Yeah. I
think of it in kind of like two ways
that we do it. So, we we haven't done
anything like paid for views or anything
like that. Although, I mean, I've I've
heard that too. It's kind of
interesting. But, we've done um more
like we're producing content and so
yeah, we're hiring folks like it could
be indie folks that live that are in
college in New York City, you know, on
the other side of the country from us.
Or it could be people that are more
local and they're just sort of like
making a bunch of content and we're
giving direction and like we have almost
like a a chat of folks that are making
content together that are coming up with
different ideas together that are that
are trying different things and that's
almost just like we are it's like our
organic content production machine I
would say and then those all get
launched and some of them do well most
of them you know get a handful of views
and you're kind of in a because of the
Tik Tok and and Instagram reels
algorithms you're sort of in like a hit
driven sort of approach there and then
we've also done and this is newer for us
but we want to do more of this of just
like actual like influencer paid
placement so that's more focus that
actually have an existing audience.
They're not like small Tik Tockers.
They're like they might have a million
followers already and we'll we'll collab
with them to make a video for their
account that then they'll post and then
like you know that will on average those
will do much better of course but of
course that's more of a okay well you
know what's your average views you know
like yeah what's your price send me the
price sheet you know kind of kind of
situation. So this so the first approach
this like stable of creators are you're
launching it to their personal Tik Toks
and you're kind of it's almost like
almost semi-inousing, right? Like you're
creating like an in-house like content
team kind of but then they're also
pushing it to their own brands like and
sort of just hoping the algorithm picks
it up and swoops it off basically. Yeah,
that's exactly right. And like they
might not even be like professional
creators, right? It's a side gig for
some folks. Okay, that's interesting cuz
I imagine in a lot of ways that's a lot
more cost effective cuz you give it like
a little bit of degree of siration so
it's not coming from like tolen official
account or whatever but you get a lot of
creative control probably the I would
assume the costs are lower than working
with the Kardashians or whatever. Is
that an approach you found others were
doing or did you kind of like iterate on
that and can come to that yourselves or
I don't know that's interesting. Yeah,
there's other folks doing that. Uh you
know there's kind of a vibrant consumer
app space and and people are doing it in
totally different ways right? uh there
there's like people working with
professional creators that are charging
per view or like this and that. There's
there's all sorts of ways to do it. I
think my thought there is like because
of how the short form algorithms work.
It's actually just really powerful to
like try a bunch of angles kind of see
what clicks and the only real way to do
that I guess unless you actually do have
an in-house content team like like a
full content team that's like filming a
bunch of concepts every day is like to
have a little bit of a stable of
creators that you're that you're
regularly working with who like making
content, right? And so then you can try
a bunch of different angles and try to
post them from different accounts. We
also do a bunch on our actual like tolen
account, but we'll try some individual
separate accounts as well and kind of
see see what works. And so those you're
you're paying per post then. So you're
saying, you know, this month you're
going to do 10 posts and we're going to
pay you X and then some of those blow up
and some of them you put money behind
and then some of them just fall flat,
but you kind of learn along the way. But
but you're mostly kind of paying per
video. Yeah, it's kind of a combination
per video or like even like focus on
retainer and so on. It's a combo of
things. And then honestly, we don't even
we don't even necessarily put money
behind them. A lot of the time we have
kind of a different process for like
some of the paid ad creative that we do
and so on. But like sometimes we'll just
see, you know, if some actually catch in
the algorithm. Yeah, I was going to say
I I think there's a I mean you've
probably thought of this, but there's
probably a world where like once you get
it bootstrapped enough and you could
probably add some features in the app to
make this like more like if you had a
filter that would let you overlay your
tolen onto like an AR situation like you
could probably maybe you already have
these features but like you could build
that into like ideally like just general
users are creating these then you're not
even it's not even something you're
necessarily directing. That that's a
great point that's actually started to
happen just in the last couple weeks
really because we had some of of our
content sort of do well like now we've
sort of seen it I would call that almost
like the UGC start to really pop up and
so like we had a video where like a
woman it was like yesterday a woman like
posted Tik Tok we have no affiliation
with just talking to someone about her
favorite WWE wrestler that's like picked
up like 30 40,000 views now. One of
these will cause you a crisis but you
know take it as it goes. I say this as
you know again the revenue count analogy
is good is like you know we most of the
posts about revenue count on Twitter are
not from us you know what I mean like
it's mostly like organic and that wasn't
the case in the beginning but like once
you you have enough brand affinity and
you have enough people amped about it
it's in some ways earned media because
like you kind of had to make the product
and make it exciting and make it easy
but there is like a real and this is how
you put you know I joked about 50
competitors like this is how you build
like a defensible moat in some way is
like just get so far ahead that like
nobody's he's going to like pierce that
and like you'll capture this brain space
in the world before anybody else has a
chance to even get off the starting
line. It would be amazing. And I think
you're right that probably more people
are competitors are coming or just more
folks are going to start doing these
types of products. I've been a little
surprised actually that like people
haven't you guys are moving pretty fast.
I don't know if you might not feel it
cuz you seem like fast movers but like
give it time. Like I think I think and I
don't I think it's just anybody any
category or novel thing with sufficient
success like doesn't mean it'll be
better but there will be people that try
you know it's the way capitalism works
right in free markets there is some
defensibility in in how from the
beginning you were so character and
design focused like the work you put in
early on designing these characters.
There's actually a great post that y'all
did on designing the character that I
read a couple days ago that I thought
was fantastic how you really thought
through like should the tools have
eyebrows? Should they not? Should it be
more humanlike? And I saw even in one of
the iterations was like Finch Finch does
this where like the characters kind of
grow with you. And so I saw you had this
iteration where it was like started as a
baby and then it grew but then what you
realize is like from the very beginning
you wanted to have these richer
interactions and so you didn't use a B.
So you've done so much iteration on
animation and character and stuff like
that that is in a way kind of a creative
mode that is really hard to just fully
replicate unless this the thing about
copycats is like a lot of copycats
they're not going to go hire a really
fantastic artist. They don't understand
what's actually making it successful.
You've reason there from first
principles so you're always going to
just be better at it than anybody else.
So I I mean I'm not trying to freak you
out but like you know it'll come. It'll
come and it'll be fine. But I mean these
are things that I think in consumer apps
and of course like I think we're gloss
you mentioned it but we're glossing over
like the actual it's really hard to make
these things right and so that's been a
huge part of revenue's defensibility
from the outside it's like yeah like
there's a bunch of these other ones and
like anybody could technically compete
with this you can look at revenue be
like yeah I can imagine how to build
that but then like the actual knowledge
to build that and the time and like the
all the things that have to go into it
is less copyable than you think right
and that's the case obviously there are
certain things like IP like distinct IP
is basically not copyable at all. But
then there's a lot of like subtlety down
from there that's like hard to copy. I
think it's kind of easy at first glance
to look at something like Tolen and and
say, "Oh, well, you know, it's like
Voice AI and they might be based on GPT
and like you could kind of copy that."
But it's like once you actually start
trying to build a awesome voice AI
experience, there's a reason that there
are like two or three on the app store,
you know, there's not like dozens. It's
just really fun and feels very exciting
to be at almost like the tail end of all
of the like crazy amounts of innovation
that like if what we do is hard what
these foundational model companies are
doing is like I have personally little
comprehension of it in some ways and we
kind of sit at the end of that right
we're ultimately customers of like the
best that the anthropics and openis and
11 labses and so on of the world can
make and honestly stand in my opinion to
capture most of the value I think that's
what everybody's like speculating now
it's going to go to the app layer right
like claude you know all those companies
will do great they'll be massive but
like in terms of I think where the most
margin capture happens will be at the
cute character that you can't replicate
in an API level in my opinion. Right. So
you announced this $10 million round
just a couple of weeks ago and you've
kind of been hinting at this kind of
explosion in growth. Tell me about the
last few months of how things have been
taking off and how things have gone as
you've grown and seen some of those Tik
Toks go viral and stuff. Absolutely.
Yeah. And I want to preface by saying
like we still feel we're in pretty early
days here. It's like, you know, we're
not anywhere close to the large consumer
apps on the app store. But yeah,
basically since we launched publicly and
we announced that we were at a 1 million
R and about a month ago and that we had
about 500,000 downloads, we then
continued to see like right around that
time and and afterwards some of that Tik
Tok my rally started to happen. So we
hit like a number one category ranking
in the app store. I think we're north of
800,000 downloads now. And then the
revenue, the AR is sort of multiples of
that of where we were. So yeah, it's
been it's been super fun. I mean, I
think it feels like we're finally
getting out to a broader market, which
is always a very fun feeling as sort of
an app builder, and we'll kind of see
how we crack to that next level. Now,
you know, of course, uh the stakes are
are only raised, and you know, right now
we're primarily US only. Uh we're live
in Canada as well, but we're not really
like global in any way. We're super
excited about potentially doing
localization. We feel like we could, you
know, Tolen could be pretty cool in Asia
and and other local, but right now just
English only. And and yeah, we're really
just continuing to iterate. I mean a lot
a lot of the stuff that we announced
like the introduction of the tollin
planet and so on is all brand new. So
we're still kind of like refining it
trying to make the product as awesome as
possible and then we'll continue to try
to go broad but now that we've broken
through to one level of growth success
it's like you know we're excited to see
what gets us to the next level. What are
you thinking about I mean obviously
there's product development you can do
there's like growth those are probably
the two biggest levers and then and then
there's a third lever too which seems
like you all are like multi-time
founders so this is probably easy was
terribly hard for me which is like
building the team and stuff like that.
So, like where are you thinking now?
You've got some cash socked away. You've
actually got cash probably coming in. I
don't know. Maybe it all goes right back
out to the model company. So, it
wouldn't surprise me at this stage and
that's probably normal if it did. But
like like how are you thinking about
what the like like are you thinking
about retention now as a main problem?
Are you still just thinking about like
trying to get into as many pockets as
possible? Like what is the because it's
an interesting spot to be like sort of
postp productduct market fit sort of
like some organic stuff taking off.
There's a lot of choose your own
adventure here. Like you could go hard
on like let's drive, you know, there's a
million things. I think this is where a
lot of like mid-stage consumer apps. I
think it can kind of get really
overwhelming because you can do like
there's a million off-the-shelf growth
tactics you should be doing right now.
But like should you actually cuz it's
going to like bind you down and you're
going to add all this like all this like
infrastructure to do like retention
campaigns and d like how are you trying
to balance that and like pick what's the
most important for how big is your team?
We're like nine folks right now. Okay.
So very small like for where you're at
like they're super small. So you really
can only think about one or two things
at a time. So yeah, like how are you
thinking about prioritizing that at this
stage? You're right. There's a lot that
we could be focusing on. The kind of
north star is always just like how do we
make the product awesome? I mean I think
you said it just before this, but like
this product couldn't have been built a
year ago. Some parts of the product
couldn't have been built 6 months ago.
Some parts that exist in it today and
two years ago none of it would have even
been like fathomableish, right? So, it's
like things are moving so fast and the
northstar for us is like how do we make
like the most helpful and best companion
experience that exists and there's still
so much to build there. Right. You
mentioned D715. Is that like your
primary what are your goal your north
stars for like measuring that? I'm sure
there's vibes as part of it but like
what is are there any like metrics that
you look at as the primaries when you're
measuring that? Absolutely. Retention.
Yeah, I think has to be the north star
because and that's just like you know
there's other ways to measure retention
obviously but like that's we borrow from
the kind of games world. I know they
they frequently look at that how many
players are coming back on D70s, D15,
D30. It's just super useful for us
because if done well, the tollin
experience should collect enough
information about the user that they're
able to like resurface to the user in
helpful ways, collect enough like memory
and investment from your conversations
that we're able to like power
interesting conversations for you. If
we're doing a good job of that, then in
theory like a companion should be like
one of the most retentive products out
there, right? Because it actually is
providing real value and helping you in
your daily life. So honestly for us it's
like our job's not even close to done
until Tolen delivers that experience for
most people that try it. Yeah. You have
like two really key parts of the
retention curve, right? You'll have this
like the first one, seven, that
basically attach like are the customers
attaching to this character and like
building some sort of base relationship
and then you'll have the second
challenge which is like okay when do
like the look's like turn out and like
what's that long-term long long term and
like you need both right to like build a
great business probably the long one is
like if you guys are shooting for you
want to return that 10 million on
multiples that long one is really what's
going to allow you to build I think
that's what a lot of consumer apps
struggle with depending on what the
nature of it is is like building those
really long-term retentive cohorts. But
like the way the product is positioned,
I think you you'll have that sort of an
advantage there if you do it right. But
yeah, I mean you you all have invested a
lot in growth too, I think for the early
stage, which is good because it like
helps you really validate the whole
thing. But yeah, I mean it's just I
don't know if it's advice you ask for,
but I always felt that was the hardest
part like first postp product market fit
was just that you will I always felt we
were having to like make painful choices
about like okay we're not there's all
these things we could do like even just
localization like whatever like those
things are like feel like obvious easy
wins but you just can't and like you
have to tell a lot of people who are
looking at you being like why aren't you
X and it's like cuz there's nine of us
and like we can't right now and so yeah
it's it's and in some ways and in some
ways if the product is good like you
said it doesn't really matter like if
the product is good if you do X first
then Y or Y first then X like there's
like commutive property it almost it's
all going to like kind of come to the
same conclusion at the end there might
be some sort of like timing timing
losses there but like otherwise the most
important thing is just to like keep
doing stuff like that's that's probably
the most important you know it feels
like just judging from the feedback that
we get from users and like where we see
that having an amazing experience and
where we see you know experiences that
we feel more iffy about they're making
it so clear like what we need to build
next which is the very exciting part
right like people want like faster
conversations they want like more
thoughtful conversations they want
better quality in in the voice and the
overall like better quality in the
memory look up and so on so it's like
it's a it's very clear what we need to
build to continue to just make the core
experience better and that feels good
because it's it's it's hard stuff to
build but it's also like it's made more
clear when you have some notion of PMF
right because the users sort of just are
telling you they're like I really want
Tolen to work better in ways one two and
three right this is the peril of raising
money before that point too, right? That
100 200k so you can like eat ramen and
iterate makes perfect sense. But like
anything more than that before you have
clear takeoff is really hard cuz it's
just like now you could I'm going to say
you should do this but like you could
like take the gas off on growth to focus
on that because you've got some cash
banked. You can burn that down just make
sure you're not losing your shirt on
token fees and then like really get that
product experience right. And that's the
benefit of like raising money. You're
pulling you're pulling that growth
forward. you're borrowing money from
your future, right? So you can make some
investments now that you couldn't
otherwise versus a bootstrapped app, you
might just be hand-to-mouth the whole
time. And like somebody, and this is
always the thing that venture
capitalists will always say this, which
is like somebody's going to raise and
then beat you to it, right? Which may or
may not, I don't know how often that
actually happens, but you could see how
they could, right? Like, hey, I don't
need to focus on all this growth crap. I
can just make the product great. And
then it's kind of honestly dualingo. The
company I worked at between Mino and
Revenue Catat, we were doing language
learning for a little bit and we kind of
got schooled in that lost to Dolingo for
that reason or related to that reason
was just like they were better
capitalized. So they just made their
product free and then worked on their
product like mad. Obviously they were an
amazing team with an amazing founder and
like just probably going to be hard to
beat in any condition, but that was just
not competable with like they were
funded. They could take a loss and just
like grow and grow and grow and grow and
then they turned the monetization on and
it was game over for everybody in that
space. It's funny. It's funny you're
saying that cuz uh some of that might be
happening in consumer AI right now of
course. Uh so everybody's like trying to
take be a loss leader and like try to
capture cuz I I mean I do think this
goes into the broader AI space in terms
of consumer but like I mentioned that
most of the gains will acrew to the app
layer probably you know and I would have
thought prior to the last year that it
would be the enterprise SAS APIs like
that seems to be a very safe bet at
least of the previous era but you know
if you look at Chad GBT or like as an
example of like still has the topish r I
mean Grock is giving them a good run for
their money right now. But like that
brand association is almost the most
valuable and sticky part of it, right?
Obviously the model and what it can do
matters, but like having that brand
primacy is worth like kind of spurning
some money to get to. And that you guys
might be in a similar situation. I don't
know. I mean I mean the only thing that
I add to what you were kind of saying a
little bit earlier is like we actually
being forced because of high token costs
to monetize relatively early on has
actually been kind of a real help to our
both growth and then also product
development, right? cuz like we're not
kind of wasting money on growth right
now. Like we're growing at a pace that
is we're outpacing obviously the money
that we're spending on on growth. So no
specifics but like we are not uh we're
not like overspending on growth or we're
not really spending net money on growth
at all of course. So because of that
because we're charging and because it
sort of gives us like a pretty stable
platform to actually be investing in
growth on where we have like money
coming in. Not every consumer AI
experience is leading with that. That
also provides a really nice or helps
define the northstar for product
development too, right? Because we have
paying customers. We can see when
certain customers decide to renew for
month two or or don't or month four or
month six or whatever. We don't have too
many month six customers yet. Only only
a handful. But yeah, we can see it's
just a much more clear signal than like
someone who like stopped playing with
the free app after 12 days or something.
Yeah, monetization is a forcing function
for product. You have to deliver the
value or people are just going to churn.
I mean, that's the thing I think a lot
of people miss about subscription apps
is that aspect of, you know, why is my
churn 70% after year one? Well, it's
that people will pay to play, but then
you got to actually deliver. And it
sounds like that has become that kind of
forcing function for you, which is super
healthy as far as like you're not just
validates the value. Yeah, it validates
that you are actually creating value.
One other thing I did want to touch on
in the funding announcement, one of the
things I think you or one of the
co-founders said was that and I imagine
this was kind of the pitch to VCs as
well is that part of your goal is to
build this kind of generalizable
technology for where Tolen might not be
the only product you create and of
course we've seen this with Dolingo.
They're getting into math and other
learning spaces where they've kind of
created this learning engine. How do you
think about that about and how did you
pitch that of like we're creating this
kind of foundational technology that can
then be applied to other areas not just
we're not just raising for a single app
what it seems like the pitch was for
sure. Yeah. So I mean we've obviously
invested a lot in designing the Tolen
characters and the way they look and
feel and the animation and so on but I
would say the the largest source of our
investment far as a team as far as
engineering of course is on the sort of
system that actually powers the
companion itself. leading with voice AI
but also text also like a complicated
memory system right like all this stuff
that just makes incredible companion
interactions possible and it's totally
the case that our audience is sort of
young women and that's obviously a very
wide audience it's it's a great audience
it's very fun to be building for them
but there's other audiences out there
and they might not be spoken to by Tolen
in its current form you guys were saying
a little bit earlier there's just no way
that uh companions or AI companions are
going to be one thing there's going to
be a lot of different variants and
versions of it. There's going to be some
people that are really into like the
Siri floating orb kind of thing. There's
going to be some people that are really
into maybe Tolen specifically. And then
there's going to be people that are
really into like cool anime girl or
something, right? So yeah, you telling
me this makes me think of Niantic as
like a as a a core example, right? Where
they built this like crazy AR tech and
then brought that to a bunch of like
premium brands. Is that something you
would ever consider? I mean, it's so
early days. You don't want to say yes or
no to anything, but like I could see
that being a future path as you like
figure out how to make this thing, you
know, world dominating. Yeah. Niantic,
they just sold Pokemon Go. I I don't
know if Oh, they sold it off. They sold
off Pokémon Go and they're Niantic is
actually refocusing their whole company
around those core technologies and they
sold Pokemon Go off. So, yeah. Did they
sell it, I assume, to the Pokemon
Company? No, to a gaming company. I
think it was Scopely. Interesting. Yeah.
So, how are you thinking about that?
Nic. Yeah. Super cool example. Yeah. I
think uh I think the way that they like
built new kinds of game experiences
obviously Pokémon Go being the largest
but also like Pikmin Bloom and others
powered by this like new yeah totally
new technology right that people hadn't
seen before but then like this whole
system around that but totally GPS that
provided a possible gameplay experience
that just like didn't exist by any other
company before and it was a very hard
thing for others to come and compete
with of course to do it in the way that
they did it well and with the depth of
knowledge and all that and when you
think of like premium brands like they
don't want to think of that right So I'm
sure that's was was thought of but I
could see that I could see that being a
path for you all as you scale.
Definitely an inspirational story for
sure. Yeah. Awesome. Well, I think we
need to wrap up. But man, it has been so
much fun chatting with you. This is such
a fascinating topic. And then and again
I think you know for those who made it
all the way to the end here even if
you're not working on the cutting edge
of AI and applying AI in this net new
way I think there's a lot of inspiration
to draw from just the capabilities of
like making your onboarding more
personal of using AI in novel ways even
in some of these more boring apps that
there's a lot of inspiration to draw.
So, I think this is going to be an
interesting listen even for those who
aren't net new creating new products and
new experiences in that way. Oh, I don't
know. I think we might have just spawned
a couple tolling competitors. AJ, I'm
sorry.
It's good. Just get ahead and buy them
out. That's the strategy. You You'll get
there. You'll get there.
Oh, man. Well, as we're wrapping up,
anything else you wanted to share or are
you hiring? Anything else that our
audience might be interested in? Yeah,
absolutely. Well, you know, I know the
audience, the folks listening to this
app are probably very heavy mobile app
developers, designers, and so on. And we
are hiring, especially for the iOS
developer position that we have open. If
you build awesome iOS apps, please, and
you're interested in what we're doing at
Tolen, please uh reach out. Awesome.
Yeah, hopefully you'll get some interest
from this podcast. We definitely have a
lot of folks listening who uh you know,
indie developers who might be looking
for a full-time gig and stuff like that.
So, yeah, definitely reach out to uh AJ
if that sounds fun. We have an awesome
small team, most of whom have totally
done indie projects or even worked on
their own startup. So, um, I think indie
developers would be very at home
building tool with us. Awesome. Thanks
again for joining us. Cool. Thanks,
guys. Thanks so much for listening. If
you have a minute, please leave a review
in your favorite podcast player. You can
also stop by
chat.subclub.com to join our private
community.
[Music]